builderdepot.co.uk 2018-12-18

# Privacy Policy

We at Builder Depot are extremely committed to ensuring that your data is strictly private and will be as transparent as possible in regards to the data we collect about you and how we may intend to use it. As part of the service we aim to provide to our customers, data may have to be shared with 3rd parties. This privacy policy describes in detail how we process your information and what your legal rights are in regards to your personal information that we may store.

In this privacy policy and our terms & conditions, the terms Builder Depot, we, us, our or other words to this effect represent Builder Depot Ltd, a private company registered in England and Wales. The term you represents the person whose information we hold as a result of an interaction you will have had with us.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act), the data controller is Builder Depot Limited of Devonshire House, 1 Devonshire Street, London, W1W 5DF.

**Information we may collect from you**

We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Location (IP address)
  * Contact details (email address and phone number)
  * Your correspondence and communication history with us
  * Transactional history
  * Marketing preferences
  * Payment card
  * Shopping habits with us
  * CCTV imagery (in-store)

**How we use your data**

Builder Depot (including our trusted partners) will use the information:

  * in order to provide you with the goods and services
  * to manage your web/credit accounts with us
  * to verify your identity
  * for fraud prevention detection
  * to tailor our website for an enhanced shopping experience
  * in Customer services related enquiries
  * in sending you related marketing emails (with your consent)
  * for marketing purposes, to better understand your shopping behaviour (assuming you accept cookies)
  * to notify you about changes to our service (with your consent)
  * in circumstances where we have a legal right or duty to use or disclose your information (for example in relation to an investigation by a public authority or in a legal dispute).

**Cookies**

As with most websites, our site ([www.builderdepot.co.uk](http://www.builderdepot.co.uk/)) uses cookies to track online user information. Cookies are small data files that are installed on device (mobile, tablet or PC) that can help track if one returns back to shop on our site. Some cookies are essential for the successful running of our website.

Cookies are split into two categories: those are critical in the functionality of the website; and those that are deemed ‘non-critical’, which help us tailor your experience with us. Upon first entering our site, you will be prompted by a cookie consent form. By either ‘accepting’ or ‘declining’ our cookies, these cookies in question will only apply to the ‘non-critical’ cookies, thus not affecting on our website functionality.

Our cookies don't store sensitive information such as your name, address or payment details, they simply hold encrypted information that help only us, better understand your user behaviour and interaction with our site as part of the compilation of our analytics and/or remarketing data.

**Google Analytics**  

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our Site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the Site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the Site, where visitors have come to the Site from and the pages they visited. If you do not allow these cookies we will not be able to include your visit in our statistics. You can read the full Google Analytics privacy policy at: <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.

**Google Tag Manager**  

This cookie is associated with Google Tag Manager which we use to load scripts into our website pages.

**Zendesk chat**  

These cookies are set to provide online web-chat support. Each user’s email address and name is provided to Zendesk chat to enable our support personnel to respond to queries from users. This feature may be disabled if desired.

**Google Adwords/DoubleClick**  

DoubleClick uses cookies to improve advertising. Some [common applications](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/) are to target advertising based on what’s relevant to a user, to improve reporting on campaign performance, and to avoid showing ads the user has already seen.

Cookies themselves contain no personally identifiable information. Depending on the publisher’s and user’s settings, information associated with cookies used in advertising may be added to the user’s Google Account.

If a user opts out of ads personalization using Google’s [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads), they will no longer receive personalized advertising from Google.

**Bing Ads**  

Bing uses cookies to improve advertising and record anonymous information about user behaviour, where the user has originated from a Bing search or advert.

**Where we store your personal data**

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where you have chosen an account password, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to best prevent unauthorised account access.

**Your rights**

You have the following rights:

  * right of access (to ask for a copy of personal data that we hold about you)
  * right of erasure or to be forgotten the (to request that we delete personal data held on you in circumstances where we no longer have any legal reason to retain it)
  * right of rectification (to ask us to update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal data that we hold about you)
  * right to object (to opt out of any marketing communications that we may send you and to object to us using / holding your personal data if we have no legitimate reasons to do so)
  * right to restrict processing (under certain circumstances you may ask us to secure and retain the data for your benefit but not otherwise use it

 If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, please contact us at Builder Depot Limited, Devonshire House, 1 Devonshire Street London, W1W 5DF, England or email us at [info@builderdepot.co.uk](mailto:info@builderdepot.co.uk)

**Third party links**

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from third party websites, namely the websites of our partner networks, informational videos and affiliates.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own terms and privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.

**How long do we keep your data?**

We will not retain your data for longer than necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy. Different retention periods apply for different types of data, however the longest we will normally hold any personal data is 6 years.

**Age**

To register with us you must be 18-years of age or older.

**Changes to our privacy policy**

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

**Contact**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to Builder Depot Limited of Devonshire House, 1 Devonshire Street, London, W1W 5DF or [info@builderdepot.co.uk](mailto:info@builderdepot.co.uk)
